[music]
How's everyone doing today?
>> Awesome. All right. Um, excited to to be
here and today I want to share a little
about uh AI coding modalities. Um, you
know, we have the IDE, CLIs, cloud. Uh,
this is going to be a pretty high level
overview. talk about the trade-offs,
talk about how to use them, how we use
them. Um, you know, really just like a
learning experience for for everyone
right now, I think. Um, my name is Yang.
I'm the CEO and technical co co-founder
of a startup called Fonzi. We do AI
recruiting. We help engineers find jobs
at AI startups. We work some of the work
with some of the hottest uh fastest
growing seed series A, series B startups
in New York and SF. Um and so you know
what we do is we've built a better way
to find jobs for engineers. Um
previously I was a software engineer at
Oscar Health and Google before that. Um
if you want to reach me my email is
yangfonzi.ai.
So um
little high level you know people
there's been new term that's been coined
this year called vibe coding. Uh and
then what is the difference between that
and AI coding? Uh people kind of like
put that in this similar bucket. So vibe
coding is development that's done fully
with AI tools and so you don't need to
be an engineer to vibe code. You don't
need to be technical to vibe code. It's
a conversational way to produce
software. Uh AI coding is some similar
techniques but it's actually based on
regular software development. So it's
rooted in how software engineers develop
software and then applying AI to get
leverage on top of that. Uh so there's a
big spectrum of tools here. So on the on
the one hand you have uh vibe coding
tools like replet, bolt, lovable. Uh
these are getting a lot of traction. Uh
in the middle you have maybe some more
conversational but still um still uh
engineer focused tools. and then you
know fully like IDE based tools that are
just designed for engineers from the
ground up. So today we're going to be
talking about AI coding not vibe coding.
I assume this is a definitely a more
technical audience
>> who is interested in writing code. Um
and I want to talk a little bit about
the different tools that have come out
um in the past few years and especially
the past few months that have like
changed how uh engineers are writing
code. So um ID CLI cloud are the main
ways this has emerged. Um just curious
uh based on the audience who's who's
using like an IDE like AI editor like
cursor. Um okay cool. Who's using
something like clawed code? So working
in the terminal? Yeah. And who's uh
using web agents cloud agents right now?
Okay so a good mix. Some people are
using multiple. Um, great. So, yeah,
just here to talk a little bit about
each of them.
So, you know, idees, this started with
uh GitHub copilot. This is where it all
started. You put the AI directly in your
code editor, usually VS code or for VS
code. Um, this is what engineers are
familiar with. I would describe this as
like pair program with AI. You make a
suggestion, AI, write some code. it's or
fancier autocomplete some people like to
call it. This is where uh you know the
first really AI coding uh things really
uh got traction. Um and this is the most
control right like you're writing code
AI is writing code you it it's side by
side you prompt it you autocomplete. Um
you're still working in the codebase
primarily.
The next uh modality that came out was a
CLI. So these instead of uh you work in
a terminal, you work in a command line.
Instead of working in the IDE, you're
talking to the AI. You have that
conversation and then AI makes changes
to your codebase on behalf of you. Um
and in order to make this work, uh it
basically needed access to better tools.
It needed access to reasoning. So you
could give it very sort of like vague
instructions and would read your
codebase, learn about uh try to figure
out what your intent was and then
translate that into code, right? So a
lot of like reasoning, a lot of um back
and forth tool use that agentic loop. Um
this has also taken off very quickly. Uh
the first thing was clawed code in
February and you know feels like it's
been out forever but it's yeah this is a
relatively new thing in our toolbox
right now.
Um and then finally taking to its
logical conclusion I guess we have
cloud. So this is a version of the CLI
tool but it's uh unlike the CLI tool
which is still interactive and like real
time the cloud one uh is more
asynchronous. you can kick off multiple
uh agents in parallel. This is uh you
know this was the first real one real
release was open AAI codeex cloud and so
you can have basically an army of AI
agents kind of doing work for you at the
same time. Right? So uh but very quickly
all the AI coding providers um
have very quickly released all all all
the modalities as well. So um you know
we started in seems crazy four years ago
with GitHub copilot uh open AI had their
codeex which confusingly is the name of
the model that powered copilot but also
their product which was an autocomplete.
uh also in 2021 cursor sometime two
years ago and then you know this year
has been this crazy explosion of both
the CLI and the cloud agents um and yeah
I didn't even know all these things
existed until I was like putting
together the slides uh and obviously all
all the players have released all the
modalities all the products and so
really
you know if I were to say what are the
differences between these it's not It's
not that drastic. They some of them
perform maybe a little better in one
modality versus the other. Like clawed
code started as a CLI. So it's probably
better for that better tuned for that.
Um OpenAI codeex you know was first the
cloud cursor was first ID uh was the
biggest player in the IDE space. So but
really uh I would encourage everyone to
kind of like experiment and see which
one works uh best for you as well. Um
but they're all available everywhere um
basically today. And so
my advice is like which one should you
use? And the answer is yes.
Yes. Uh this has been um yeah and okay.
So
the the the answer is that it depends on
what you're you're working on. So, um,
cloud is the most, uh, autonomous,
right? It's the the one with the least
back and forth, the least amount of
feedback. So, you know, it's it's good
for easy bug fixes, copy changes, color
changes, you know, things in your
backlog that are low priority. You don't
care if it gets it right the first time.
Um, but it'd be a nice surprise if it
did. So, cloud is very good for that.
you can kick off a lot of small tasks um
without opening a code editor, right?
That's really nice.
CLI, I would say, is probably a good
place uh for core feature development.
Um things with well scoped features,
things where you can have a conversation
with the AI, plan out what you want to
do, and then have it uh have the
confidence that it can execute on that
plan correctly.
Um and then the places where the IDE I
think really shines are things where uh
you need to do some active exploration.
You don't actually know what the specs
are. You want to explore things. You
want to try a lot of different ideas
very very quickly, right? The latency
with the CLI or cloud is just much
higher. So you can change you can tweak
colors like you normally would in an
IDE, but it just helps you type faster.
So that's like, you know, a place where
I think the ID is still the best. Um,
another place where you uh people like
to use ID, I think, is when it's outside
of, you know, the the typical training
data. If it's if you're not on the happy
path, if you're doing something weird or
unusual, chances are the um the AI is
not going to be able to write large
amounts of code correctly on its own. So
for things that um are pretty specific
or niche uh you you it's hard to get as
good results of the CLI and cloud. Um
yeah, so it depends uh depends on your
task. I think there's a there's room
right now for all of the different
modalities and you know these categories
will also change over time, right? As
the models get better, as the the
harnesses that power these things get
better, I expect more and more projects
to move up the up the chart, right? Uh
things that used to require being done
in the IDE will be able to be done in
the CLI and things that really required
active management management of the
agents in the CLI, maybe the maybe you
can start oneshotting more easily in the
cloud. So as capabilities emerge, you
know, I expect this um this chart to
also evolve as well.
Cool. Um kind of want to talk about some
typical workflows that we use at my
company to develop software. Um and
stuff you know seen at some other
companies as well. Uh this is what I
call like sort of the default the happy
place as of like you know November 2025.
uh a lot of development kicks off in the
CLI. There's a conversation, there's
planning, there's like with the AI to
really get the scaffolding and it writes
a lot of the the big pieces together, a
lot of the boiler plate, a lot of the
scaffolding, like putting all of that
together and then you go into the IDE to
really fine-tune specific things, change
specific lines, tweak things, tweak
copy. Um it's faster to maybe like uh do
the polish in the IDE. um before your
feature gets released. So I would say
this is probably the the default the way
to do it as you know of course this is
all going to change in like six months
but this is uh kind of like a happy
medium right now.
Um
this one uh since we're in New York and
we take the subway I call the commuter.
Uh this lets you you know kick off tasks
in the cloud. So instead of having that
conversation in a terminal, you can
actually just have that conversation in
a in an app or in browser on your phone.
Uh and so you can have some back and
forth iterations with a cloud agent on
uh on your phone in the subway. And
it's, you know, it won't be immediate.
You don't need perfect internet
connection. The answer comes back when
it does, but you can kick off a lot of
the work. And then once you get to the
office uh then you can actually uh you
know get the branch or all the work
that's been done put it in your IDE or
your CLI and then actually uh continue
developing and polishing before uh you
know that code is ready for production.
So this is like a brand new way to
develop software. I can now write code
on the subway, which is, you know,
without pulling out a laptop, which is
kind of like a
incredible new new uh way to approach
it, right?
And then um
finally, we have
what I call the the agent manager. And I
think this is directionally where things
are are are going to go, right? as the
AI beames becomes more capable and as we
become better at prompting and guiding
the AI, you'll be able to do more and
more tasks in the cloud. And so, you
know, you'll this is kind of the dream,
right? Instead of uh managing
a team of junior engineers to kind of do
work, you'll be able to manage an
infinite number of cloud agents to do
all your tasks, right? So, you'll give
them contact, you'll kick them off. Um,
occasionally, you know, uh, you'll need
to manually clean up the code and polish
it before release, but, you know, this
is sort of like the the true leverage of
the 10x engineer is having this
swarm of agents that are like constantly
working in parallel in the background in
the cloud. So, um,
we're not there for today for most for
most tasks. the you know the AI is
certainly not capable enough but you
know I think this is where people this
is where things are going
um cool
thanks
[applause]
any questions
>> any uh contrarian points of view I I
personally uh I I quite uh feel the
sitting on the train uh writing some
code in in my phone and then arriving at
work and the code being written. I love
that. And I'm not sure if that's the
dream. I think the dream is sitting on a
beach. Uh really, [laughter]
that would be my idea. Yeah. Any
questions? Sorry, I'll just jump over.
Hey. Um, I I love what you said, but I I
think that there's something I haven't
seen quite yet, which is like a tooling
dedicated for front-end QA and adding
that to like the overall workflow as as
part of the process of refining AI
developed code. I find often that my
front end work isn't where it needs to
be and then I'm like having to copy
paste images in and manually debug. I'm
I'm literally trying to set up like a
playright sub agent right now to see if
I can get that working. Um, but have you
seen anything in that space that can
help me with my QA pipeline?
>> Yeah.
[laughter]
>> Yeah. I I I I think in terms of the
agentic solutions, there are there are
tools out there like Devon which will uh
which was uh one of the you know first
AI coding agents that basically will run
the code and then QA it and then if it's
wrong it'll like debug it itself and and
stuff like that. Uh that probably works
for like more functional QAing. uh for
visual QA. It's I'm not I'm not sure
I've seen a good example of AI with like
good visual taste like fixing your
designs yet. At least not not yet.
>> So in the third example, you said we're
not really there yet, right? In this
this multiple agent or what would it
take to get there? What are we missing?
Um,
that's a good question. I I think part
of it is
getting better at part part of it is
going to be the models like
understanding intent better and
understanding context of the business.
But sometimes that's not really going to
happen without us also providing a lot
more context whether it's like agents MD
or rule cursor rules, right? like giving
the
the the agents need more business and um
and product context is is sort of the
thing that I'm really finding. Um
there's also probably just going to be
better workflows around how we plan and
you know maybe make specs. That's like a
that's like one answer that's I think
getting pretty popular is like being
more clear up front of what the AI
should do and so that you can basically
like have it one shot the
>> I think you're right the the spectrum
and stuff I found has been very useful
for keeping it on rails but I would say
that I work for Tessle um uh on the on
the subject of um visual stuff I I just
remembered a friend of mine wrote a
video game library in love 2D and he
wanted to be able to QA. So he wrote an
agent that looks at the screen and runs
it at like 0.1 frame a second and
analyzes the screen contents to see, you
know, if the player is moving, if the
aliens are moving or that, I think if we
can get to the point where, you know,
the AI can look at a screen and know
exactly what it's seeing, you know, I
think that helps. Um, if someone's
interested in that, I can I can find the
link. It's on GitHub. Um, but there's
another question here.
Yeah. Uh, regarding the commuter method
that you were talking about, um, where I
I haven't I know that you can call
Claude from GitHub, just at Claude. Are
you doing this? Have you tried doing
this from you said on your phone like
from the Claude app on your phone or I'm
just curious what ways have you been
doing this?
>> Yeah. So,
uh,
yeah. So, so cursor has a has a cloud
mode. Um,
cloud agents, I think they're called.
Uh, OpenAI background agents. Sorry,
can't keep up. The OpenAI codeex cloud
has a has a version. And Cloud Code web
launched I think like two weeks ago. So,
they have another UI that's not just the
janky GitHub issue
thing. Yeah,
>> I've I've used a tool on that topic
called typing mind. I don't know if
you've heard of that. Just Google it.
typing Mind and um you can run an agent
on your laptop as like a gateway from
Typing Mind directly to your machine and
have an MCP that can has access to
specific folders on your file system.
And so on my phone I can sit and have a
conversation with an AI like in typing
mind and that uses my my um keys to get
to Claude and Gemini and all the others
and it can create files on my file
system. So it actually writes the code
on the file system and then commits that
to git. So I I can just have the
conversation on the phone either
verbally or um Yeah. So you don't need
your computer to be
>> well you need the computer where the
files are going to be it's got to be
written somewhere. Uh but yeah you you
could put that in a cloud instance
somewhere like AWS or a droplet or
somewhere. Yeah.
>> I don't know if anyone's tried the VS
code tunnels feature and then you can
access your VS code from whatever your
dev box is in the browser even like from
anywhere. So I can use my regular VS
code setup from my browser
>> until Yeah, until it gets blocked. So
>> yeah,
>> I do that the cheap way with tail scale.
So
>> scale
>> tail scale the face. Uh sorry.
>> Yeah. Yeah. These
the cloud stuff is is nice. They've like
kind of abstracted all this. They spin
up sandboxed VMs basically for you
automatically. And so you never even
like think about have to think about any
of that. So um definitely super
convenient.
Yep. On my way.
>> Hi Yang, thank you for the presentation.
Uh so my question is about hiring. As
you said, Fonzi helps with uh hiring in
terms of prospects. So I'm a recent
graduate looking for jobs as well. And
uh my question to you is two parts
basically. First, how does Fonzi help
with that and what kind of AI
implementations do you use? And second
part of the question is I myself tried
to build some automations or like AI
related solutions to like find postings
or like scrape website data concise it
and use it to you know create custom
resumes or things like that. Do you
think these kind of workflows sit in the
workflows that you've mentioned or do
they get like better as we move with
time and all of these AI tools keep
showing up?
Yeah. Um I mean I could talk for hours
about Fontsy and how we're different. Um
I have five minutes.
>> I have five minutes. Great. Uh I I'll
try to keep it short. Um I I think the
and I I'll I'll keep it pretty high
level instead of diving too deep into
the the specifics of our product or
anything, but fundamentally I think what
we're seeing with recruiting is AI being
applied to a nonAI world. So, you know,
we we have job boards, we have job
postings, right? This is historically
how people find jobs. And all of a
sudden, AI is really good at writing you
a 100 cover letters, tweaking your
resume based on job description of a
bunch of companies and, you know, kind
of making up stuff that you haven't done
just to match the job description. Um,
and so what's it's it's created this
crazy problem where uh there are
thousands of applicants applying for
every single open role. there's so much
noise that the recruiters either spend a
week going through it or just give up
and because most of them are relevant or
they're hallucinated resumes and then uh
and then the candidates don't hear
anybody it's don't hear it back. So now
the candidates are using AI to scale how
much applying they're doing. So it
actually just creates a you know it's a
flywheel um or death spiral how however
you want to call it of just bad
experiences for both candidates and uh
companies. And so Fonza fundamentally
what we're trying to do is cut through
all of that, try to figure out who's
actually good, who's actually on the
market um and then figure out which
companies are actually hiring and then
you know that's it. That's the
marketplace. It's it's much much smaller
but much much higher signal than you
know a job board. So we're we're
thinking about how to do this properly
from an AI native perspective is the is
the short answer. Um
second part of the question I think was
like how is AI going to affect this? I
think AI is a huge role to play. Uh like
the existing system is just again the
spiral the death spiral is already
happening so it's only going to get
worse. Um we have to like I think
reinvent how people
uh hire and how people find jobs. And
so, you know, we're trying to approach
it from first principles with an AI
native focus.
>> Any other any other questions that don't
relate to death spirals?
[laughter]
>> Keep it positive.
>> Okay. Uh I think that's everything
you've done. Anything else? Thank you.
Yeah. Thank you so much. [applause]
Heat. Heat.
[music]